<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://vadimus.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://vadimus.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-27T13:15:36+00:00</updated><id>https://vadimus.uk/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Vadimus</title><subtitle>A place for me to flex and develop my writing muscle.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Tell the world’s saddest joke</title><link href="https://vadimus.uk/tell-the-worllds-saddest-joke.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tell the world’s saddest joke" /><published>2023-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://vadimus.uk/tell-the-worllds-saddest-joke-</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://vadimus.uk/tell-the-worllds-saddest-joke.html"><![CDATA[<p>The citizens of the United States of America elected Donald Trump as their president.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="642-things-to-write-about" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The citizens of the United States of America elected Donald Trump as their president.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Extreme Emotional Sensitivity</title><link href="https://vadimus.uk/extreme-emotional-sensitivity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Extreme Emotional Sensitivity" /><published>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://vadimus.uk/extreme-emotional-sensitivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://vadimus.uk/extreme-emotional-sensitivity.html"><![CDATA[<p>I was just watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PYM-sS-0-yg">an interview by Russell Howard with Jordan Peterson</a> and he mentioned something that really hit home.</p>

<p>It’s well known that he went through a period of depression but I’ve never heard him describe it in so much detail in previous interviews. He speaks about how he was extremely sensitive to sensory inputs, to the point where he couldn’t listen to music because it affected him so much. I immediately recognised this as something that changed in me after my friend Amber died in 2016. There are many more things that overwhelm me with emotion since that happened, from music to films to any depiction of people experiencing great joy.</p>

<p>The most recent example was something of a shock to me when it happened. I was perusing YouTube, following the recommendations wherever they took me, and I came across the video below.</p>

<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4ic7RNS4Dfo"></iframe>

<p>Even looking up that embed code and seeing the first few seconds I could feel the emotion starting to overtake my body.</p>

<h2 id="wasted">Wasted?</h2>

<p>I’ve long thought that I may have wasted my life. At this point in my mid-40s I “should be” married with 2.4 kids, a fulfilling job, and a great and active social circle.</p>

<p>I think I have a fulfilling job, recent health-related absenses notwithstanding, which I really enjoy. Most of my colleagues are great and very supportive, and I feel like I’m actually doing some good most of the time. I’m finding various aspects of the company’s growth from startup to, err, whatever the next stage is, to be incredibly frustrating, but I wouldn’t necessarily characterise it as bad.</p>

<p>My social circle is limited but fantastic. Covid has greatly affected this, at least I think it has - when I look back at recent years I’m not so sure it’s had as much of an effect as I want to think it has. Since Amber got sick I’ve struggled to maintain social activities; she was always a driving force behind that in my life. I’m not great at maintaining social ties on my own, never had been.</p>

<p>As for being married and having kids, there’s not even a flicker of hope that it might happen. I could write long passages on why I think that is but it ultimately boils down to the fact that I can’t fathom the possibility that anyone would want to date me, never mind commit to a relationship and even contemplate sharing the responsibility for other living things with me.</p>

<h2 id="self-worth">Self-worth</h2>

<p>This, I think, is the core of my struggles. I don’t consider myself worthy of much. And the self-confidence I do have is often surrounded by lashings of self-doubt and caveats. I know I’m conflating self-worth and self-confidence but I feel they are intrinsically related; you can’t have one without the other.</p>

<p>Starting with social activities and extending to dating, I don’t think enough of myself to believe it’s possible that people would want to spend time with me, much less be interested in my opinions. It’s for this reason that I don’t really start conversations in social situations, not even in the WhatsApp and Telegram group chats I’m part of. And when I do weigh into a conversation I quickly lose confidence in what I’m saying.</p>

<p>What I find a little odd is that if I think I’m right in a conversation I will sometimes gradually get more agressive with the people who disagree. I can be very stubborn when I think I’m right and I’m not overly invested in the long-term opinion the person or people I’m talking to have of me. This isn’t something I do consciously, but I’ve definitely observed this behaviour in myself.</p>

<p>Which brings me to the one context in which I feel most confident…</p>

<h2 id="professional-worth">Professional worth</h2>

<p>Most of the time I feel quite strongly that I am good at my job. Certainly not perfect, but good. It’s often also surrounded by lashings of self-doubt and caveats, but for the most part I consider myself to be a better-than-average software engineer, and a competent software architect (which is my chosen area of speciality).</p>

<p>For the most part this view of myself has been reinforced by colleagues and bosses throughout my career. I’ve made my share of mistakes but feedback has overall been very positive.</p>

<h2 id="split-personality-or-a-natural-consequence">Split personality, or a natural consequence</h2>

<p>So what I seem to have is something of a split personality, confidence-wise. Work is fine, but my personal life is something of a shit-show.</p>

<p>I was bullied at school. A lot. Geeky, fat, bespectacled, and socially awkward, though I’m not sure whether that last trait was there from day one or was also a result of the bullying. I learned over the years to shrink into a corner and be as quiet as I can. And I still do it now.</p>

<p>When out at the pub, or at any other social occasion, you’ll find me off to the side, often alone, just people watching. I love people watching - they’re fascinating. But you’ll have to get me pretty drunk to get me up and dancing, or the centre of attention in any size of group.</p>

<p>I can handle one-on-one conversation; I’m good at that. I’ve been told I’m a great listener, and I’ve also been taught I share way to much way too soon with strangers. I’m not sure if that’s a problem or not, it certainly hasn’t been so far but I may just have been lucky.</p>

<h2 id="am-i-happy">Am I happy?</h2>

<p>Sometimes I think I am, but I also think that’s probably because I’ve resigned myself to accepting that this is who I am. I struggle to think that I deserve anything more.</p>

<h2 id="does-it-matter">Does it matter?</h2>

<p>I don’t know, but I’m trying to find out.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was just watching an interview by Russell Howard with Jordan Peterson and he mentioned something that really hit home.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Empty Theatre</title><link href="https://vadimus.uk/the-empty-theatre.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Empty Theatre" /><published>2021-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://vadimus.uk/the-empty-theatre</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://vadimus.uk/the-empty-theatre.html"><![CDATA[<p>I like empty theatres, before the cast, the crew and the audience arrive. The gathering of chairs assembled to take in the majestic stage. The lights, poised to illuminate the magic as it happens.</p>

<p>There’s an eeriness to the feeling of walking down the aisle, footsteps on the carpet mutedly echoing around the vast empty space in which people will later experience another world. Arriving at the stage the clicks of my shoes resonate off the lofty ceiling as I climb the seven wooden steps to the apron.</p>

<p>Turning to face my ghostly audience I pause to take in the epic sight. Hundreds of potential eyes watch me clickety-clack across the stage, my gaze drawn travelling from the blaconies on the left, across the upper circle, and down to the balconies on the right, all perfectly framing the bulk of my admiring fans.</p>

<p>I look up to find a complex web of metal poles, lattice structures, and wires for miles. There are more poised lights here, of all shapes and sizes, with coloured plastic attached to their faces promising a spectrum of moods. I trace a particularly intricate web of wires across and down to one side of the stage, where it ends as a rope with rubber grips. A harness, and a promise of some Peter Pan action later.</p>

<p>There’s a red light glowing in the dark recesses of that side of the stage. I dare to explore it and find a corridor. Proceeding cautiously I skulk toward the other end, uncertain of what I will find. The corridor is painted jet black and the single red bulb hanging from the ceiling barely lets me make out the edges of the passageway. Further along I find a door, also painted jet black, even the handle. I push it down and out; nothing happens. I push it down and in; the door opens.</p>

<p>I find myself in an alleyway outside the theatre. The smell in the air and the pools of water on the cobbled surface indicate it’s been raining. It’s getting dark; nearly time to perform.</p>

<p>Exiting the alley to the front of the theatre I make a turn and enter the theatre once more. Turning again I arrive at my home for the evening. I have a simple task as the show is sold out, so I settle in for a night of tearing tickets and wait for my ghostly audience to materialise.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="five-minute-writer" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like empty theatres, before the cast, the crew and the audience arrive. The gathering of chairs assembled to take in the majestic stage. The lights, poised to illuminate the magic as it happens.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Reaction Was Instinct</title><link href="https://vadimus.uk/my-reaction-was-instinct.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Reaction Was Instinct" /><published>2021-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://vadimus.uk/my-reaction-was-instinct</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://vadimus.uk/my-reaction-was-instinct.html"><![CDATA[<p>It was an insignificant dose, but I couldn’t see past what they were. I don’t need these; I don’t take these, so why was I holding two packs of them, enough for two months?</p>

<p>It comes down to my feet. I have type II diabetes and my feet are starting to become very numb. I can hold my big toes in my fingers and not feel it in my big toes. Uh-oh. I called my GP for a podiatry referral which he happily arranged, and then he suggested I start taking a pill to slow the progress of the numbness. Ok, fine, I can do that.</p>

<p>From the pharmacist I merrily skipped with a song in my heart and some pills in my hand, until I got home and read about what I was holding. It seems these pills, this numbness-slowing wonderdrug, was an antidepressant.</p>

<p>In hindsight my reaction was daft. It was pre-programmed by years of hearing stories from friends and the media about how destructive these things can be. It was pure instinct to make excuses to not take them. I talked myself into knots when I thought about it, but at the end of the day I had no reason to not trust my doctor. This was a well-known off-label use of this drug, and after calling my doctor again and confirming that I had the right pills I started taking them.</p>

<p>It’s a tiny dose compared to what the instructions in the box say the minimum dose should be. They’re unlikely to have the effect documented in those instructions, but they will promote blood flow to my extremeties, which is what I need right now.</p>

<p>Initial instinctive panic aside I’ve made my peace with the fact that this means I now take an antidepressant. I feel I need to delve deeper into why this is such an issue for me, but for now here’s hoping they stave off the loss of a foot or two, at least for a little while.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was an insignificant dose, but I couldn’t see past what they were. I don’t need these; I don’t take these, so why was I holding two packs of them, enough for two months?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">It Didnt Seem Like Much At The Time</title><link href="https://vadimus.uk/it-didnt-seem-like-much-at-the-time.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It Didnt Seem Like Much At The Time" /><published>2021-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://vadimus.uk/it-didnt-seem-like-much-at-the-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://vadimus.uk/it-didnt-seem-like-much-at-the-time.html"><![CDATA[<p><em>It didn’t seem like much at the time</em>; it never seemed like much at the time, but the effects were cumulative. I didn’t notice the gradual withering away of any sense of self-worth, and it seemed like nobody else did either.</p>

<p>I don’t know when the depression started. I don’t know why it wasn’t identified. I don’t like thinking about how my life might be different had it been treated early on. I don’t like feeling that it’s not possible to undo it at this late stage.</p>

<h2 id="it-begins">It begins</h2>

<p>I wore glasses and I was a geeky nerd, and I still don’t fully understand why that made me such a target. I think it even started before I wore glasses but my first memory of anything happening is being called “four-eyes”. I was a geeky nerd first, bespectacled a bit later, and as the effects cumulated I became overweight. I very quickly and unintentionally developed poor eating habits as a way to cope with what was happening; it was just another flaw for them to point out, repeatedly.</p>

<p>I never fought back so maybe that explains why I became a staple target; I just took it and probably visibly retracted further into myself each time. Chances are I was giving the perpetrators exactly what they wanted without even realising it. I was, without any awareness, encouraging them to continue doing it, day in, day out.</p>

<p>I didn’t see any point in telling an adult about it since many of them witnessed it happening and yet showed no signs of wanting to help. The only outcome I could fathom is that it would get worse. Rules of the playground are a very real thing and the punishment for breaking them can be extreme; it was not worth the risk. In my mind there were levels of torture beyoond what I was currently experiencing and I wasn’t going to invite any escalation.</p>

<p>So I continues to let them chip away at me. I’m not sure I ever got a chance to decide who I was or who I wanted to be. I mostly did what I was told, was definitely several teacher’s pet, and was probably several teacher’s worst nightmares. I was not academically gifted unless I was actually interested in the subject, and for me that meant anything to do with computers. Since it being the late 80s and early 90s this did not help my geeky nerdy image as the geek revolution was yet to begin.</p>

<h2 id="some-relief">Some relief</h2>

<p>I found some outlets. To put it another way, I found some hiding places. The school had a number of rooms that contained upright pianos and these could be booked for breaks and lunch, something I did whenever possible. I can’t play the piano particularly well even with all that “practice” but it was somewhere for me to spend what should have been social time with my fellow pupils in a way that didn’t involve exposing myself to the way they treated me.</p>

<p>In later years the school bought a computer-based music making system. I don’t remember much about it other than the room it was in. It was set up in a windowless storage room on the second floor off the stairwell at one end of the school. It had a lock on the door and you had to book the key out to use it. This meant I could lock the door and forget the world existed for the duration of breaks and lunch hours. I can’t say I every produced anything worth listening to using that system but it was a place where I could be calm in a place where I invariably struggled to be at all.</p>

<p>I focused on the music because while the school did have computers they were not something you could generally use outside of I.T. classes. This changed in my final years at that school but it was too late to have much of an impact for me. I regret not asking for more access as I feel it would have been immensely beneficial for me, but the possibility didn’t really occur to me at the time.</p>

<h2 id="different-situation-same-story">Different situation, same story</h2>

<p>My life throughout school was simply a chain reaction with very little self-direction; I mostly did what I thought was expected of me.</p>

<p>I was expected to fail my A-levels. In fact my A-level Physics teacher told me exactly that, so I went out and got a job. I was then surprised when Bournemouth University, my first choice, accepted me with fairly low requirements… which I then met. I decided to defer entry for a year and I dearly wish I could remember exactly why. I think it may have been a timing thing. Whatever the reason I can practically guarantee it wasn’t really my decision so much as the way the current took me.</p>

<p>So I spent my first year following school in retail only to find that nothing had changed, or so it seemed to me. It’s frustrating how looking back on periods of your life can result in a completely different perspective. At the time I never felt like I fitted in with the other staff. In many ways it felt exactly like school but with hindsight I’m pretty sure I was creating that feeling myself. Wherever you go you cannot get away from yourself.</p>

<p>I can remember a number of moments, interactions with them where I injected a spin that wasn’t there. Maybe I’m looking back with a need to remember a better experience, who knows. What I do know is that even after leaving school I’ve rarely allowed myself to be open to genuine relationships in or out of work so as to protect myself from harm. I think I need to explore this in more detail.</p>

<h2 id="all-about-the-computers">All about the computers</h2>

<p>I was working at PC World, initially in the sales department. It didn’t take long for me to realise that I was not cut out for selling people stuff they didn’t need, which is basically the whole purpose of the sales staff in that store. It took the store manager a little longer but he got there within a few months of me achieving barely adequate sales numbers.</p>

<p>I requested a transfer into the tech support department but was told that required qualifications. The only vacancy I was qualified for was store merchandiser. It’s odd to me that someone who had been tinkering with computers most of his life and who had previously worked weekends and school holidays as a computer technician in a tiny computer repair shop should be deemed unqualified but I didn’t see any point in arguing with them. This should have been another in a sequence of clues that something about the way I valued myself wasn’t quite right.</p>

<p>I jumped head first into the role I had unintentionally landed. I thought myself CorelDRAW, studied the corporate documentation on how the merchandising process worked, and very quickly got the trust of the store management and head office such that I was left to run my department of one without much oversight. I was paricularly proud of the pre- and post-Christmas sales, organising all staff who were working on Christmas Eve to completely change the look of the store in just a couple of hours. This was not something I was in any way qualified for having never been great at organising myself nevermind others, but for whatever reason I was motivated to succeed at the task and succeed I did.</p>

<p>After Christmas I was offered a role covering telephone support post-Christmas. I jumped at the chance and again I seemed very motivated to succeed. Following on from that I was offered a role on the customer service desk. Apparently my combination of technical knowledge and being able to talk to customers, especially the difficult ones, had been noticed. Apparently I was still not qualified to move into the tech support department. Again, I didn’t argue with them.</p>

<h2 id="university">University</h2>

<p>I then went to university and did the course I wanted to do because nobody expected me to do anything else. It’s odd but I can’t unravel the actual reason I went to <em>that</em> university and did <em>that</em> course; I guess it doesn’t really matter. I knew I wanted to do something related to software engineering, and my experience at PC World had taught me that I had some level of natural people skills so the combination of software engineering and management made a lot of sense, I just wish it had been conscious at the time. Maybe it was and I just can’t remember, but whatever the reason that’s where I found myself.</p>

<p>University was much the same experience as school and PC World, except that there were more places where I felt I belonged. I was finally around people who shared my interests in a way I’d not experienced before. Yet, for some reason, I still felt out of place.</p>

<p>I found more outlets so I could cope. Continuing to eat poorly was definitely a big part of it, but I also embedded myself into helping manage the computer labs. This was a mostly solitary role providing support to other students. It was paid but didn’t pay much. I did it because it was a way to get more access to the computer labs that were reserved for the more senior students.</p>

<p>The 24/7 computer labs mostly contained macs and were geared towards people being able to surf the internet, work on assignments and print them out. I wanted access to the unix boxes, specifically they were HP/UX machines. These were tightly controlled as there weren’t many of them and demand was high. Joining the support team was the easiest way to get more time with these machines and the support needs in those labs were minimal. So long as there was a spare terminal during my shift I could use it.</p>

<h2 id="social-life">Social life</h2>

<p>In case it’s not clear yet I was largely a hermit at university. I did not get on very well with the people in the house where I lived for my first year. I made some friends but always through circumstances. I somehow landed in a social circle with another house in the student village and managed to maintain a semi-active social life with them. This grew over the years following as we moved around the area surrounding the campus, and I’m still in touch with them today. But even now I feel like an outsider in that group, and it’s something I’m good at unintentionally persisting despite their efforts to include me.</p>

<p>The third year of my degree required me to spend a “year in industry” and I was equal parts excited and anxious about it. I landed a decent position with a company that developed and sold nuclear monitoring systems, and as it turned out it was not a position that should have been occupied by an undergraduate. As with previous things I threw myself into it hard and found some success with it.</p>

<p>I think this is the time to talk about the difference between the shriveled up shell of a man that was created during school and the man who recognises that he has repeatedly proven his worth in every work role he’s ever had.</p>

<h2 id="the-line">The line</h2>

<p>There is a very well-defined line between my social self-image and my professional self-image. Professionally, aside from suffering from fairly standard imposter syndrome I’m fairly confident regarding my skills and abilities. Personally I’m anything but.</p>

<p>Up to this point in my narrative I’ve had a number of jobs, including some casual and part-time work that I’ve not bothered to include. On balance I’ve always had positive feedback but I’ve never felt like I belong anywhere. I have no reason to believe that I didn’t, or don’t. I’ve had very few bad experiences interacting with other people since school and yet I’m socially a very quiet and withdrawn person. I don’t reveal much of myself I think because I’m convinced that if I let them see who I am and what I think I’ll be back at school and I don’t believe I could survive any more of that.</p>

<p>There another line and it exists in both the social and professional arenas, but more so on the social side. I’m quite a different person one-on-one than I am within a group. I’m very open but a group of more than two will almost completely shut me down. This makes no sense to me except that, maybe I feel like I can explain myself far better when I’m not competing for airtime with a group of people. I’m not someone who can talk over other people or interrupt them without feeling very guilty. This leaves me at a massive disadvantage when part of a group discussion. And I think the reason is that I don’t think anyone wants to hear what I have to say; the views of everyone else in the group are more important so interrupting doesn’t feel right most of the time.</p>

<p>I have a similar view on over-talking and interrupting in professional groups but I’m more confident in what I have to say so will do so if I feel it’s important. In fact I’ve had feedback from a couple of people I’ve worked with that when I think I’m right I can be downright arrogant about it. I’m actively working on recognising and curtailing that tendency.</p>

<p>I do something similar in personal contexts but it comes out slightly differently. I won’t argue my point for long and will shortly shut down from the social situation I’m in and internally try to work out whether I was actually right or wrong. According to my family this comes across as sulking which is not a good look past 40 years old.</p>

<h2 id="and-now">And now</h2>

<p>So here I am, in my mid-40s, with most of the character traits discussed above still large and active parts of my daily personality. The writing prompt that triggered this self-reflective trip down memory lane was <strong>it didn’t seem like much at the time</strong> which I connected to the extensive bullying I endured at school. I can’t say with any degree of confident that the root of the way I am can be traced back to that but it makes a lot of sense to me.</p>

<p>I’m like a turtle who spends most of his time in his shell. When I peek out I’m always ready to duck back in at the slightest hint of danger. And it depresses me.</p>

<p>I want to be sociable, I want to be out there. Surprisingly I actually like talking to people, I even enjoy arguing with people most of the time. I find it very difficult to open up to people but when I do I don’t seem to know when to stop. For people who know me pretty well I’m an open book; to people who don’t know me I can appear to be cold and distant.</p>

<p>I should say in closing that I’m a lot better than I used to be, but there are things I still don’t do that I think would be beneficial. I don’t date (why the hell would any woman want to spend time with me). I don’t socialise unless I feel like I must (there are certain groups of people this doesn’t apply to and several where it absolutely does). I don’t initiate conversations with people unless it’s part of my job (people don’t want to hear what I have to say). And so on.</p>

<p>Living in my head can be difficult at the best of times but I endeavour to make it a little better every day.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="642-things-to-write-about" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It didn’t seem like much at the time; it never seemed like much at the time, but the effects were cumulative. I didn’t notice the gradual withering away of any sense of self-worth, and it seemed like nobody else did either.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A conversation you regret not having</title><link href="https://vadimus.uk/a-conversation-you-regret-not-having.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A conversation you regret not having" /><published>2020-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://vadimus.uk/a-conversation-you-regret-not-having</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://vadimus.uk/a-conversation-you-regret-not-having.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m a coward, especially when it comes to putting myself out there. This is probably not news to anyone who knows me. For as long as I can remember the idea of presenting myself to others, explicitly or implicitly asking them to judge me has filled me with a paralysing dread.</p>

<p>As you may imagine this leads to many possible answers to this question, most of which are excruciatingly embarrassing, though probably not as embarrassing as the opposite question - that may be one for another, braver, version of myself to answer.</p>

<p>One missed opportunity with one particular person does stand out, and it spans a couple of decades.</p>

<p>We start in the early 90’s. I’m in secondary school enjoying myself as part of the “technical crew” - we did all of the lighting and sound for school productions, from awards ceremonies to concerts and musicals. Huge fun and a great learning experience despite being ridiculed by most of the school. By the time in question I had started to focus on sound production.</p>

<p>It was during preparation for the annual musical there that I first met Bernie.</p>

<p>My memory of the details is a bit fuzzy but I clearly remember becoming more than a little infatuated. She was either one or two years above me and perfect in every way. I can’t say for sure what was driving my reaction, but the way she carried herself, the way she spoke, all of her little mannerisms, it was all unwaveringly angelic to me.</p>

<p>No doubt she knew, and likely saw me as little more than a nuisance, but when she smiled at me I melted. I definitely didn’t hide it well, but if she knew she didn’t say anything or avoid me, which didn’t help my feelings towards her.</p>

<p>Remember what i said at the beginning of this post? I’m a coward in these situations and this was no exception. In addition to lacking the self-confidence required to ask her out I also had to deal with what I saw, at the time, as a significant age difference. If girls of the same age were a different species older girls were of a completely different branch in the evolutionary tree. So I enjoyed my infatuation from afar.</p>

<p>And was occasionally creepy. I’m not proud of this but Bernie worked in a bakery in town and I can’t say I didn’t walk past it during her shifts more often than would be considered non-creepy…</p>

<p>Anyway, enough about that. So despite many conversations with her in my head nothing happened in reality, but curiously none of those are the conversation I regret not having. My lack of self-confidence would almost certainly have taken a further unrecoverable dent if rejected at that time, at least that’s how my brain saw it.</p>

<p>No, the regretful non-conversation didn’t happen about fifteen or sixteen years later.</p>

<h3 id="older-and-not-much-wiser">Older and not much wiser</h3>

<p>After some moving around the country I eventually ended up living in Guildford, about nine miles from the aforementioned secondary school. I think it’s safe to say I was just starting my journey to self-confidence discovery (still ongoing) when I developed some very painful toothache.</p>

<p>Being a complete cretin I tend to not organise things like registering with doctors and dentists until I need them. So, as per previous similar panics I asked my friends in the area for recommendations, and a dentist called Waterden’s came highly recommended. I made an appointment.</p>

<p>Bear with me, I’m getting there if you’re not already ahead of me.</p>

<h3 id="the-physically-painful-bit">The physically painful bit</h3>

<p>Appointment one, the dentist takes a look in my mouth and tells me I need to see the hygienist for a deep clean, while also telling me the tooth that’s aching needs to come out due to the cyst on the gum underneath it. That explains the pain.</p>

<p>So, I make two more appointments, one with the hygienist for the deep clean and the other with the dentist to pull the tooth.</p>

<p>The hygienist appointment was first. Other than being told that I should take better care of my teeth it passes with no notable incidents other than suddenly being able to feel the separation in my lower front teeth with my tongue for the first time in living memory. Revelation!</p>

<p>Anywho, I returned a few days later for the extraction and while I’m in the waiting room the receptionist asks me if I went to the secondary school that I did, in fact, attend. Slightly concerned I enquired as to how she knew that?</p>

<p>“Oh, one of our hygienists saw your name and thinks she went to school with you.”</p>

<p>A short conversation later it turns out to be Bernie, and she’d like to catch up if I’m interested. She’s not working today but if I call in tomorrow I can arrange to meet up with her.</p>

<h3 id="somewhat-helpful-distraction">Somewhat helpful distraction</h3>

<p>I remember very little of the following extraction. The pulling, sure, and the odd sensations, indeed, but my brain was very much elsewhere. I was reliving my childish infatuation in as much detail as I could remember, which to be fair wasn’t much.</p>

<p>Should I meet up with her? Could I meet up with her? Would I be able to maintain the character my ever-increasing years had built or would I instantly regress to that somewhat creepy teenager and make a complete fool of myself?</p>

<p>It’s probably clear from the title of this post what happened: I totally chickened out.</p>

<p>It feels quite ridiculous to think about now. I had no idea what her life was like, but I couldn’t bring myself to let her see who I’ve become. I was embarrassed by who and what I was. I felt like I’ve failed at the game called life. In many ways I still do.</p>

<h3 id="and-now">And now?</h3>

<p>I’ve often thought whether I would do anything different if I had the opportunity again, and I’m honestly not sure. My memory of her is still “perfect” because I can attribute my behaviour to being a socially awkward teenager.</p>

<p>Would I really want to add another memory as a socially awkward adult? On the other hand it’s stuff like this that holds me back all the time from potentially bringing amazing people into my life, so in theory I’ve learned it’s worth the risk, right?</p>

<p>After some overthinking I’ve realised that everyone I am or have ever been friends with, with only one exception, has either taken the initiative themselves or was the result of a situation putting us unavoidably together for some period of time. I can be social when I see not other option.</p>

<p>This just reinforces the fact that I still lack the confidence to put myself out there, even when the potential rewards for doing so are huge.</p>

<p>What’s the point of this story? Dunno. It exposes a demon I still struggle with every day, one that limits my life in ways I don’t even want to attempt to count with no sign of a way forward.</p>

<p>Smeg!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="642-things-to-write-about" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m a coward, especially when it comes to putting myself out there. This is probably not news to anyone who knows me. For as long as I can remember the idea of presenting myself to others, explicitly or implicitly asking them to judge me has filled me with a paralysing dread.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A moment of forgiveness</title><link href="https://vadimus.uk/a-moment-of-forgiveness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A moment of forgiveness" /><published>2020-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://vadimus.uk/a-moment-of-forgiveness</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://vadimus.uk/a-moment-of-forgiveness.html"><![CDATA[<p>I can’t believe she left me.</p>

<p>I don’t have a right to expect her to always be here but i wasn’t ready for this.</p>

<p>She was outwardly so confident she wouldn’t leave, but I knew she was scared. We were all scared. Some of us still are.</p>

<p>I am.</p>

<p>This is not about her of course, not really. She faced the hand fate dealt her with such amazing grace and determination I was in awe. I was so proud of her, whether I have any right to be or not. She was a model cancer patient if ever there was one and certainly didn’t deserve what happened. I miss her so much.</p>

<p>So who needs forgiveness if not the one who “left”?</p>

<p>In reality I’m not really sure. I know I’m angry; not an uncommon emotion I’m sure but I feel incredibly selfish for feeling it. I find it curious that my first thought when writing this piece was “I can’t believe she left me.”</p>

<p>It’s not like she chose to. We drifted apart during those final months and I think I understand why. I’m fairly certain that the core of my issue is that so much of my life revolved around her, and it feels like a part of me has been ripped away leaving a jagged wound. Nearly four years later as I write this I still feel broken, which is especially tough to accept since she largely helped me fix myself ten years ago.</p>

<p>I was a broken automaton back then, blindly following my programming, never veering, never taking chances, never crawling out of my shell to experience the world around me. She showed me another way, and now it’s gone.</p>

<p>But is it really? Can I recreate it? Can I find that person I was for the first six of the past ten years and resurrect him?</p>

<p>I don’t know, but I know I want to. Probably an evolution of him rather than a simple rebirth, but I don’t know how.</p>

<p>What I do know is that it has to start with me forgiving myself for letting go of him in the first place. Whether I blame the grief, the pain, my not being equipped to deal with a loss so fundamental to my character at the time, it has to be forgiven for me to move on with any sense of purpose.</p>

<p>She’d tell me to just get on with it, and she’d be right. She’d say all the right things to help me do it too, probably without even trying. She’d be equal parts annoyed and amused at my inability to just do it.</p>

<p>She’d be exactly what I need to just get past this and get on with being. The irony is certainly not lost to me.</p>

<p>She is.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="642-things-to-write-about" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I can’t believe she left me.]]></summary></entry></feed>